My name's Conan Edogawa!
اسمي إيدوغاوا كونان
High school student Shinichi was forced to take a drug that shrunk him.
أُجبر طالب الثانوية شينتشي على تجرّع عقار قلّص جسده
If the organization learned that Shinichi and Conan were the same person,
إذا عرفت المنظمة أنّ شينتشي وكونان هما نفس الشخص
everyone close to me would be in danger!
!فسيقع جميع من حولي في خطر
The only one who knows the truth is Professor Agasa!
!البروفسور آغاسا وحده من يعرف الحقيقة
I hide my identity yet again today, in which there is only one truth!
أُخفي هويتي، والحقيقة واحدة دوماً !اليوم كذلك
Robberies, kidnappings, murders...
...سطو، اختطاف، قتل
There's just no end to these crimes...
لا نهاية لهذه الجرائم
That's exactly why your detective skills are proving so useful.
لذا مهاراتك في التحرّي ذات فائدة
Old man Kogoro gets all the credit, though.
لكنّ العم كوغورو ينال كل الفضل
All done! These are my special Criminal Pursuit Glasses.
انتهيت! إنّها نظارات ملاحقة المجرمين الخاصة التي اخترعتُها
How do I use these?
كيف أستعملها؟
Try pressing the button on the side.
اضغط الزرّ على الجانب
Sweet!
!مُذهل
It'll display the location of this transmitter within a 20-kilometer radius.
ستعرض موقع جهاز الإرسال هذا داخل نصف قطر 20 كيلومتراً
You can keep it here most of the time.
يمكنك إبقاؤه هنا معظم الوقت
It's like a sticker!
إنّه كاللاصق
Thank you, Professor Agasa!
!شكراً يا بروفسور آغاسا
My name is Masami Hirota!
اسمي هيروتا ماسامي
Please! Find my father!
!أرجوك! اعثر على أبي
Go on...
!حسناً
My father, who works away from home in Tokyo, quit his taxi driver job,
ترك أبي الذي يعمل بعيداً عن منزله في طوكيو وظيفته كسائق سيّارة أجرة
and he's been missing for a full month now!
وفقدنا أثره لشهر كامل الآن
So that's why you've come to me?
لذا أتيتِني؟
Yes.
أجل
I took time off from school in Yamagata to come look for him here!
استأذنت بالغياب عن المدرسة في ياماغاتا للبحث عنه هنا
You're the only one I can turn to now, Detective!
أنتَ الوحيد الذي يمكنني طلب !المساعدة منه سيّدي المتحري
Very well. I'll take on the case.
فهمت، سأقبل بقضيتك
This is my father, Kenzo Hirota.
هذا هو أبي، هيروتا كينزو
He's 5'9" and 48 years old!
طوله 170 سنتيمتراً وعمره 48 عاماً
What about this cat?
ماذا عن هذه القطّة؟
It's my father's cat. Its name is Kai.
قطّة اشتراها أبي، اسمها كاي
He has three others named Tei, Gou, and Ou.
يملك بالإضافة لها ثلاث قطط، تي وغو وأو
Finding people isn't really my thing.
البحث عن الناس ليس تخصصي
But if he had one of these on him, I could've found him in no time at all.
لكن لو كان يضع إحدى هذه، لتمكنت من إيجاده بلمح البصر
I know! I'll stick it on Ran and test it out!
حسنٌ، سألصقها على ران واختبرها
Here you are.
تفضّلي
What the heck are you doing?!
!ما الذي تفعله؟
Oh, nothing...
...لا شيء
The transmitter!
!جهاز الإرسال
Oh no! I stuck it there!
!تبّاً! التصق هناك
My mother died when I was little, so my father is my only family!
تُوفيت أمي في صغري، وأبي هو عائلتي الوحيدة
If anything were to happen to him!
...إذا أصابه مكروه
No. Well, not yet...
...كلا، ليس بعد
I haven't found any leads...
لم أجد أيّ دلائل
Sorry.
آسف
Masami-san again?
ماسامي-سان مُجدداً؟
That's the third time today.
هذه المرّة الثالثة اليوم
Apparently he didn't socialize much with other people,
يبدو أنّه لم يكن كثير الاختلاط بالناس
and he almost never talked about himself, according to his coworkers.
وكان قلّما يتحدّث عن نفسه وفقاً لزملائه في العمل
Goukai Teiou pulls ahead of the pack to earn his 5th G-1 victory in a row!
يتقدّم غوكاي تيو المجموعة ليربح !"فوزه الخامس المتتالي في "جي-1
Goukai Teiou? (Heroic Emperor)
(غوكاي تيو؟ (الإمبراطور البطوليّ
It's my father's cat. Its name is Kai.
قطّة اشتراها أبي، اسمها كاي
He has three others named Tei, Gou, and Ou.
يملك بالإضافة لها ثلاث قطط، تي وغو وأو
Kai, Tei, Gou, and Ou!
!كاي وتي وغو وأو
Rearrange them and...
...إن رتّبناها
This is...
...هذه
Goukai Teiou
غوكاي تيو
...nothing important.
لا شيء يستحق الذكر
Goukai Teiou truly is invincible!
!غوكاي تيو لا يُقهر بحق
Yeah, that has to be it!
!أجل، هذه هي بالتأكيد
Hirota-san loves horse races!
يُحب هيروتا-سان سباقات الخيول
So he named his cats after a famous horse!
!لذا سمّى قططه بناءً على حصان شهير
Hey, Dad!
!انظر يا أبي
Hey, now!
!لحظة
I bet you can find him at the race track!
!يمكنك إيجاده في مضمار السباق بالتأكيد
Wow! This is my first time at a race track!
!مُذهل! أول مرة آتي لمضمار سباق
Let's hurry and find Masami-san's father.
لنسرع ونجد والد ماسامي-سان
Yeah, right! Like he'd be that easy to find!
حمقاء، كأن الأمر سيكون بتلك السهولة
Don't be mocking us detectives!
لا تستخفي بالتحرّي
There he is!
!ها هو
See! I'm such a great detective!
!رأيتما؟ أنا مُتحرية عظيمة
No way!
!مُحال
I'll go get him!
!سأجلبه
Wait! He's purposely gone missing.
انظري! اختفى عمداً
We don't want to scare him away and then lose him!
لا نريد إخافته ثم فقدان أثره
But...
...لكن
We'll follow him back home.
سنتبعه لمنزله
I've been looking for you for so long!
!كنتُ أبحث عنك لوقت طويل
Dad!
!أبي! أبي
Good for her!
هذا حسن
Doesn't something seem different about her?
أليس هناك أمرٌ مختلف فيها؟
She's wearing more grown-up clothes,
ترتدي ثياباً ناضجة أكثر
and it looks like she has makeup on.
كما تضع مساحيق تجميل
She hasn't seen her dad in a long time!
لم ترَ والدها لوقت طويل
Of course she'd wear make up!
بالطبع ستتزين
That case was as easy as pie in the hands of Kogoro Mori!
!كانت قضيّة يسيرة بين يدي موري كوغورو
Who's that?
من ذاك؟
He's dead?!
!ميت؟
We found him after he hanged himself last night.
وجدناه بعدما شنق نفسه البارحة
What a pain!
يا للإزعاج
What about his daughter?!
!ماذا عن ابنته؟
Daughter?
ابنته؟
You know, Hirota-san's daughter? The one who came looking for him?
ابنة هيروتا-سان التي أتت للبحث عنه
Something wasn't right about him.
كان هناك ما يثير الريبة به
He said he'd pay me a full years' worth of rent all at once
قال أنّه سيدفع إيجار عام كامل دفعة واحدة
if I let him have an apartment with no questions asked.
.إذا جعلته يقطن الشقّة بلا طرح أسئلة
Plus all the bills were brand new and crisp!
كما كانت العملات جديدةً لامعة
My guess is if his daughter did come over, then she's probably dead too.
إن أتت ابنته فلعلها ماتت أيضاً
What do you mean? I thought Hirota-san committed suicide...
ما قصدك؟ ظننت هيروتا-سان قد انتحر
The police said it was a murder.
قالت الشرطة أنّها جريمة قتل
Yes, it was a homicide.
أجل، كانت جريمة قتل
He was hung from the ceiling after he was killed.
عُلِّق من السقف بعدما تمّ قتله
Judging from the large hand marks on the victim's neck,
،بناءً على علامات اليدين الكبيرة على عنق الضحية
the murderer must have been quite a large man.
فالمجرم كان رجلاً ضخم البنية غالباً
What about his daughter?!
!ماذا عن ابنته؟
These were lying on the floor near the scene of the crime.
كانت هذه على الأرض قرب مسرح الجريمة
These are Masami-san's glasses.
إنّها نظارات ماسامي-سان
Her body hasn't turned up yet, but I'm pretty sure that she's...
...لم نجد جثّتها بعد، لكنها غالباً
Come on, now. Don't be so depressed.
هيّا، لا تكوني محبطةً هكذا
But Masami-san might've been murdered!
لكن ربما قُتلت ماسامي-سان
And she just found her father, too! How horrible!
!بعدما وجدت أبيها أخيراً... يا للفظاعة
We still don't know for sure that she was murdered!
لا-لا نزال نجهل إن قُتلت حقاً
We can't give up yet!
!لا يمكننا الاستسلام
But now what? If only we had a clue to go by!
...لكن ما العمل؟ لو كان لدينا خيط ما
That's it! I accidentally put the transmitter on her!
!أجل! جهاز الإرسال الذي علق بها
Perfect!
!هذه هي
Hey, kid! Where are you going?!
!أنت! أين تذهب يا فتى؟
The fact that it's moving means Masami-san might still be alive!
تحرّكه يعني أنّ ماسامي-سان قد لا تزال حيّة
Come on! Make it in time!
!بسرعة! لأصل في الوقت
A pachinko parlor?! What's Masami-san doing here?
صالة باتشينكو؟! ماذا تفعل ماسامي-سان هنا؟
Oh no, the battery's dying!
!كلّا! البطارية تنفد
I have to find her quick!
!لأجدها بسرعة
Ain't no kids allowed in here!
!ليس مسموحاً بالصبية هنا
Get out!
!اغرب
The battery's dead.
نفدت البطارية
Hey, you! Why were you gone so long?!
!أنت! لمَ تأخرت هكذا؟
Oh, you know...
...فـ-فقط
What's up with Ran?
ما خطب ران-نيتشان؟
She's been like that for a while now.
كانت هكذا لفترة
She must really be worried about Masami-san.
القلق يلازمها حيال ماسامي-سان
Something's weird about that guy.
هناك أمرٌ غريب في ذاك الشخص
He's been looking up here this whole time.
ينظر نحونا منذ فترة
He's the man who was hanging out by Hirota-san's apartment!
إنّه الرجل الذي كان يتسكع !قرب شقّة هيروتا-سان
Come to think about it, the killer was a large man!
صحيح، كان القاتل رجلاً ضخم البنية
He killed Masami-san's father?
هو من قتل والد ماسامي-سان؟
Wait right here! I'll go catch him and find out where Masami-san is!
حسنٌ، انتظري يا ران! سأذهب للقبض عليه ...وأعرف أين ماسامي-سان
Where's Masami-san? What's happened to her?!
!أين ماسامي-سان؟ ماذا حلّ بها؟
Tell me!
!انتظر
I caught him!
!أمسكته
Good work!
!أحسنتِ
What great luck! Who'd have thought the killer would come to us?!
!يا لجرأة المجرم ليأتي بنفسه لنا
Killer?! You've got it all wrong!
!المجرم؟! أخطأت الفهم
Yeah, right! Then who are you?!
!اخرس! من أنت إذاً؟
I'm the same as you!
!أنا مثلك
What?!
ماذا؟
I'm a detective too!
!أنا مُتحرٍّ أيضاً
Actually, I, too, was asked to find Hirota-san.
تلقيتُ طلب البحث عن هيروتا-سان بدوري
By this man.
من قِبل هذا الرجل
That's that guy!
...هـ-هذا الرجل
I'm really a detective, I swear!
!أنا مُتحرٍّ صدقاً
Then why did you run away?!
!لمَ هربت إذاً؟
That young woman came after me, so I instinctually...
...ركضت الفتاة نحوي، لذا هربت غريزياً
I've always been sort of a coward...
لطالما كنتُ سريع الخوف
I wear these sunglasses so people can't make fun of me.
أرتدي هذه النظارات كيلا يسخر الآخرون مني
Enough of your stupid excuses!
!يكفي أعذاراْ سخيفة
Get serious! Masami-san's life is at stake here!
!تصرّفا بجدية! حياة ماسامي-سان على المحك
Yes, I know.
أعرف
So you were asked to locate Kenzo Hirota-san as well, then?
إذاً، تلقيت طلب عمل بالبحث عن هيروتا كينزو-سان أيضاً؟
Yes. But there was something strange about his family...
أجل، لكن كان هناك أمرٌ غريب في عائلته
This was the man who hired me!
هذا الرجل هو من وظّفني
He asked me to find his brother who left Kyushu for Tokyo.
طلب مني البحث عن شقيقه الذي غادر كيوشو نحو طوكيو
He said his brother was his only relative.
قال أنّه قريبه الوحيد
His only relative?
قريبه الوحيد؟
Masami-san was supposed to be Hirota-san's only relative!
يُفترض أنّ ماسامي-سان هي قريبة هيروتا-سان الوحيدة
That's weird, too! Masami-san's father came here from Yamagata!
!هذا غريب أيضاً! أتى والد ماسامي-سان هنا من ياماغاتا
That is strange.
غريب بالفعل
There can't be two Hirota-sans...
لا يمكن أن يكون هناك اثنين من هيروتا-سان
There's one other thing that's strange.
هناك أمرٌ إضافيّ غريب
I heard this from the taxi company that Hirota-san worked at.
سمعتُ من شركة سيارات الأجرة التي كان يعمل فيها هيروتا-سان
Apparently he would drive the same route every single evening,
،أّنه يسلك نفس الطريق كلّ مساء
without bothering to pick up any passengers!
دون الاهتمام بنقل ركّاب
And he would do this at breakneck speeds!
!كما يفعل ذلك بسرعة عالية
He was just letting off steam.
كان ينفّس عن ضغوطه فقط
Happens all the time to middle-aged men.
أمرٌ شائع لدى الرجال الذين في مُنتصف العمر
So, who is this client of yours?
من عميلك هذا إذاً؟
Akira Hirota. 28 years old. He's a large man, over 6 feet 3 inches tall.
هيروتا أكيرا، 28 عاماً. إنّه رجل ضخم البنية يفوق طوله 190 سنتيمتراً
A large man?!
!ضخم البنية؟
That's right.
أ-أجل
Could he be the large man the inspector was talking about?
...أيمكن أنّه الرجل ضخم البنية الذي قصده المفتش
Tell me! Did you tell this man anything about Hirota-san?!
!إذاً، هل أخبرت هذا الرجل شيئاً عن هيروتا-سان؟
Yes, of course...
أجل، بالطبع
And then it was after that that Hirota-san was murdered.
ثمّ بعد ذلك قُتل هيروتا-سان
So I wondered if there was any connection...
لذا تساءلت إن ما كانت هناك صلة
That's it! This man murdered Hirota-san!
!أجل! قتل هذا الرجل هيروتا-سان
And then he took Masami-san with him!
!ثمّ أخذ ماسامي-سان معه
Well? How can I contact him?!
!أخبرني! كيف أتصل به؟
He contacts me!
!هو من يتواصل معي
So you don't have any clues?
لا خيوط لديك إذاً؟
Sorry...
آسف
It's him!
إنّه هو
There's no mistake! It's the man I ran into at the pachinko parlor.
لا شكّ، إنّه الرجل الذي ارتطمت به في صالة الباتشينكو
But why did the transmitter on Masami-san's watch lead me there?!
لكن لمَ أخذني جهاز الإرسال على ساعة ماسامي-سان إلى هناك؟
If he really is the killer, and he was wearing Masami-san's watch...
...إن كان هو القاتل حقاً، ويرتدي ساعة ماسامي-سان
...then she's already...
...فهي قد
...been murdered!
قُتلت بالفعل
Hurry and recharge it, Professor!
!أسرع وأعد شحنها يا بروفسور
Stop rushing me! Being impatient isn't going to help you any!
لا تعجلني، التسرع لن يعطيك ثماراً
But if we don't hurry...
...لكن إن لم نسرع
Say, do you remember the robbery from the other day,
أخبرني، أتذكر جريمة السطو
the one where they stole a billion yen?
التي سُرق فيها مليار ينّ ذاك اليوم؟
Yeah, the one with the trio of thieves?
التي نفذها ثلاثة لصوص؟
A security guard was killed when he recklessly tried to stop them.
قُتل حارس أمن حاول إيقافهم بتهوّر
That's what he got for taking them lightly.
ذلك ما ناله جرّاء الاستهانة بهم
Calm, cool, and collected...
هادئ ومتّزن ومربوط الجأش
That's your style, isn't it?
أليس ذلك أسلوب هولمز الذي تحبّه؟
I get it.
فـ-فهمت
Is he really in this hotel?
أهو في هذا الفندق حقاً؟
Definitely! I saw him go in on my way home from school!
!بلا شكّ! رأيته في طريق عودتي من المدرسة
That's strange! The transmitter hasn't moved at all for a while now!
غريب، لم يتحرك جهاز الإرسال لفترة
He didn't take the watch off and escape, did he?!
أيمكن أنّه خلع ساعته وهرب؟
Yes, he's staying in Room 802.
أجل، إنّه يقيم في غرفة 802
Come on, hurry up!
!بسرعة، تعال
Who'd have thought he was really here?
من كان ليتصور أنّه هنا حقاً؟
Just when I'm in a hurry, too!
ونحن في عجلة
Thank you!
شكراً لكم
Open up! I know you're in there!
!افتح! نعرف أنّك هنا
It's open!
!إنّه مفتوح
He's dead!
!إ-إنّه ميت
This sweet smell... it's potassium cyanide!
هذه الرائحة الحلوة... سيانيد البوتاسيوم
I see. He couldn't live with what he had done so he killed himself!
فهمت، لم يستطع العيش مع تأنيب جريمته فأقدم على الانتحار
We should contact the police!
علينا الاتصال بالشرطة
That's Masami-san's watch.
إنّها ساعة ماسامي-سان
So he did take it from her.
أخذها منها بالفعل إذاً
Empty duralumin cases.
حقائب دوراليومين فارغة
Wait!
لحظة
Two separate, yet conflicting requests to find the same person...
طلبان منفصلان متناقضان للبحث عن الشخص نفسه
Kenzo Hirota-san acting strange and driving the same route everyday...
يتصرّف هيروتا كينزو-سان بغرابة ويقود بسرعة عالية على نفس الطريق يومياً
And then these cases...
...وهذه الحقائب
What if...
...أيمكن
Huh? Hirota-san was single?!
!ماذا؟ هيروتا-سان أعزب؟
Yeah. He didn't have any daughters.
أجل، لم تكن لديه ابنة
Plus he was born and raised in Tokyo.
كما أنّه من أهل طوكيو مولداً ونُشأة
That can't be!
!لا يمكن
That's it! I have this case figured out!
!هكذا إذاً! فهمت هذه القضية
These empty cases are the key to unlocking this mystery!
تلك الحقائب الفارغة هي مفتاح حلّ لغز القضية
Masami-san, Kenzo Hirota, and Akira Hirota...
ماسامي-سان، هيروتا كينزو، وهيروتا أكيرا
Now that we know they're not relatives,
بعدما عرفنا أنّهم ليسوا أقارباً الآن
they have no connection whatsoever!
فلا صلة بينهم أبداً
But in the context of the other recent incident,
،لكن في نصّ الحادثة الأخيرة قبل أيام
the entire mystery comes unraveled!
!يُحلّ اللغز بأسره
They're the three thieves who stole the one billion in yen!
!إنّهم اللصوص الثلاثة الذين سرقوا المليار ينّ
Judging from the number of cases here,
،بناءً على عدد الحقائب هنا
they must have been filled with the stolen money.
فقد ملأوها بالمال المسروق غالباً
If so, then the reason Hirota-san sped down the same route every day
في تلك الحالة، فسبب إسراع هيروتا-سان بالسيّارة على نفس الطريق يومياً
was to rehearse their getaway!
!كان للتمرن على هروبهم
Their plan succeeded, but he took all the money for himself and ran.
نجحت خطتهم، لكنه أخذ المال لنفسه وهرب
He betrayed them.
خانهما
Eager to catch Hirota-san, the two partners concocted lies
سعياً للإمساك بهيروتا-سان، اختلق الاثنان قصّة كاذبة
and sent separate detectives to locate him.
وأرسلا مُتحريّين منفصلين للبحث عنه
And then when he was found, he was killed.
وعندما وجداه، قُتل
Killed by the large man, who was then killed in this very room.
من قِبل الرجل ضخم البنية، ثمّ لقي هو حتفه في هذه الغرفة
Killed by the woman who claimed she was Hirota-san's daughter.
قتلته المرأة التي ادّعت أنها ابنة هيروتا-سان
Perhaps she was the mastermind behind these murders!
لعلّها كانت المدبرة الرئيسية لهذه القضيّة
Wait!
!لحظة
Her hairstyle and overall appearance were different,
...تسريحة شعرها وملبسها مختلف
but her build and the number of suitcases she had weren't!
!لكن بنيتها وعدد الحقائب لم يكونا كذلك
Where are you going, Conan-kun?!
!أين تذهب يا كونان-كن؟
I found Masami-san!
!وجدت ماسامي-سان
Ran! Hurry!
!ران-نيتشان! بسرعة
Hey, kid! No cutting in line!
!أنت يا صبي! لا تقطع الصف
Our dad's gonna be chopped into pieces and buried alive in the mountains
سيُقطع أبي أشلاءً ويُدفن حيّاً في الجبال
if we don't hurry and save him!
!إلم نسرع وننقذه
G-Go right ahead...
...تـ-تفضلا
Follow that taxi!
!اتبع سيارة الأجرة السابقة
What about the mountains?
ماذا عن الجبال؟
The reason she seemed different the second time we saw her
سبب اختلاف مظهرها عندما رأيناها المرة الثانية
was because when we found Hirota-san,
هو لأنّه عند عثورنا على هيروتا-سان
she was in a hurry and hadn't completed her disguise!
كانت في عجلة ولم تكمل تنكرها
And then Hirota-san's reaction when he saw her...
وردّة فعل هيروتا-سان عندما رآها
That wasn't because he was surprised to see his daughter.
لم تكن دهشة رؤية ابنته
It was because he was terrified of the partners he betrayed
بل رعب انتقام الرفيقين
coming to exact revenge on him!
!اللذين خانهما
Damn it! Why didn't I realize it sooner?!
!تبّاً! لمَ لم أدرك مسبقاً؟
What now? We lost her!
!ما العمل؟ فقدنا أثرها
I'm 100% certain she entered this harbor!
!أنا واثق أنّها دخلت هذا المرفأ
She's definitely somewhere nearby!
!لا بدّ أنّها قريبة
Conan-kun!
!كونان-كن
Where's the money, Masami Hirota?
أين المال يا هيروتا ماسامي؟
Or should I say, Akemi Miyano-kun.
أقصد، ميانو أكيمي-كن
Okita-san! What's going on?!
أوكيتا-سان، ما الذي يجري؟
The sleeping drug you gave me to put him to sleep...
...العقار المنوم الذي أعطيتني إيّاه لأنومه
The instant he drank it, he fell to the ground and stopped moving!
فورما شربه، سقط على الأرض وتوقف عن الحركة
Explain!
!اشرح
What he had in brute strength he lacked in intelligence.
كان وفير القوة البدنية، لكن فقير الفكر
There's no doubt that he would alert the authorities
لا شكّ أنّه كان سيلفت انتباه السلطات
by throwing all his money around the instant he got it.
بإنفاق كلّ نقوده يميناً ويساراً فورما يأخذها
As long as someone that dangerous remained alive,
ببقاء شخص مثير للمخاطر مثله على قيد الحياة
my own plans would be hindered.
كانت خطّتي لتفسد
You intended to kill everyone from the start, didn't you?!
كنت تنوي قتل الجميع من البداية إذاً؟
Now hand over the money.
سلّمي المال الآن
It isn't here! It's being held at a certain location.
ليس هنا، حفظته في مكان ما
I'm sick of you using me!
!سئمت من استغلالك لي
I'm through with this!
!سأنسحب
Do you honestly think that is an option?
أتظنين بإمكانك ذلك؟
I do.
أجل
After I escape overseas, I'll let you know where the money is.
سأخبرك بموقع النقود بعدما أغادر البلاد
We can't have that, now. As long as you're alive, my plan is in jeopardy.
لا يمكن ذلك، ستكون خطتي في خطر طالما تبقين حيّة
Once you're dead, all links to me will have vanished.
بموتك، ستختفي كلّ الخيوط التي تقود لي
I can easily find any number of replacements for you and the other two.
يمكنني إيجاد بدلاء لك ولهما بكلّ سهولة
Getting my own hands dirty goes against my principles,
تلطيخ يديّ يعارض مبادئي
but it will be the finishing touch.
لكنها ستكون اللمسة الأخيرة
How simple-minded.
يا للسذاجة
Kill me and you'll never know where the money is.
إن قتلتني لن تعرف أين المال أبداً
I have a pretty good idea where to find it.
لديّ فكرة عن مكانه
You did a good job. Allow me to express my gratitude by killing you.
أبليتِ حسناً، لذا دعيني أعبّر عن امتناني بقتلك
Masami-san!
!ماسامي-سان
Take this!
!خُذ
Are you alright?
أأنتِ بخير؟
Just a scratch.
مجرد خدش
You're the boy from the detective agency!
!أنت الصبيّ من وكالة التحرّي
How did you know I was here?!
كيف عرفت أنّي هنا؟
My transmitter!
!جهاز الإرسال
Transmitter?
جهاز الإرسال؟
When we first met at the agency, I accidentally stuck it on your watch.
عندما أتيتِ في البداية للوكالة، التصق الجهاز بلا قصد على ساعتك
After following the signal, I arrived at the hotel and then ran into you.
تبعت الإشارة ووصلت الفندق حيث التقيتك
Seeing you with all the large suitcases,
،بعد رؤيتك بتلك الحقائب الكبيرة
I realized you were leaving with the billion yen that you stole.
أدركت أنّك كنتِ تغادرين بالمليار ينّ التي سرقتها
Who are you?
مـ-من أنت بالضبط؟
Conan Edogawa. A detective.
إيدوغاوا كونان، مُتحرٍّ
I had no idea there was anything on the watch.
لم أكن أعرف أنّ هناك شيء عالق بالساعة
But the watch belonged to that big man, right?
لكن كانت تلك الساعة تخصّ ذاك الرجل العملاق، صحيح؟
No, he broke his own watch when he lost control and killed Hirota-san,
كلا، كسر ساعته عندما فقد أعصابه ،وقتل هيروتا-سان
so I gave him mine.
فأعطيته ساعتي
This guy intended to kill everyone from the very start, didn't he?
نوى هذا الرجل قتل الجميع من البداية، صحيح؟
Yes.
أجل
Hirota-san realized this,
أدرك هيروتا-سان ذلك
so he betrayed us before we knew what was happening.
لذا خاننا قبل أن نعلم ما يحصل
Does that mean this man is the mastermind behind the billion-yen robbery?
أيعني ذلك أنّ هذا الرجل هو العقل المدبر لجريمة سطو المليار ينّ؟
That's right. Okita scouted for people he needed to realize his plan.
أجل، بحث أوكيتا عن الأشخاص الضروريين لتنفيذ خطته
He would put these people into teams and have them commit robberies.
يقوم بجمع أولئك الأشخاص في فرق ويرسلهم لارتكاب عمليات السطو
Rumor had it that he would eliminate his recruits to keep them silent
كانت هناك شائعات بتخلّصه من أتباعه لكتم أفواههم
after they would finish his jobs,
،بعد إنهائهم عملهم
but I didn't know it was the truth!
!لكن لم أتوقع أنّها الحقيقة
You're not going to run away?
لن تهربي؟
I'm tired.
أنا مُرهقة
I'll tell you where the suitcases with the one billion yen are!
!سأخبرك أين هي الحقائب بالمليار ينّ
The front desk of the hotel, right?
مكتب استقبال الفندق، صحيح؟
How did you know that?!
كيف عرفت؟
When you got in the taxi, you didn't have the suitcases with you.
لم تكن الحقائب معك عندما صعدتِ سيّارة الأجرة
I simply assumed that...
...فتوقعت
You're really something.
أنت مُبهر حقاً
That's enough!
!مكانك
You talk too much, woman!
!أنتِ ثرثارة يا امرأة
Masami-san!
!ماسامي-سان
Who's he?!
!مـ-من هذا؟
The boss behind the billion yen robbery!
زعيم عملية سطو المليار ينّ
Just as she had said, the billion yen was being kept at the hotel.
كما قالت، كانت المليار ينّ محفوظة في الفندق
The bill codes matched those of the stolen money.
طابقت أرقام العملات المال المسروق
Thus the billion-yen robbery case came to a close.
فأُغلقت قضية سطو المليار ينّ
Thank you, little detective.
شكراً لك أيّها المتحري الصغير
Up there!
!هناك
The shot came from the top of the building across the river!
يوجد أشخاص فوق البناء على !الجانب الآخر للنهر
What does this coded number message say?!
ما معنى رسالة الأرقام المشفرة هذه؟
They could be road numbers!
قد تكون أرقام طريق
Like Route 162, you know?!
مثل الطريق 162
Get this helicopter moving, Inspector!
!سيّدي المفتش! بسرعة! المروحية
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
The Mysterious Sniper Message Case.
قضيّة رسالة القناص الغامضة
Next Conan's Hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Take a good look at a regular electronic calculator.
!حاسبة الكترونية عادية، أمعنوا النظر لها
Next episode, try reversing your thinking.
!جرّبوا النظر بالمقلوب في الحلقة القادمة